[
  {
    "name": "Maths",
    "id": "food",
    "theme": "green",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "single-select-item",
        "question": "What is the value of sin(30)",
        "options": [
          "1/2",
          "3/2",
          "1/3",
          "1/4"
        ],
        "answer": 0
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select",
        "question": "Who was the one to discover zero?",
        "options": [
          "Newton",
          "Jeff Goldblum",
          "Aaryabhatta",
          "Shrinivasan Ramanujahn"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "In which American State did chili con carne originate?",
        "answer": "Texas"
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "What is the correct name for a cluster or bunch of bananas?",
        "options": [
          "Foot",
          "Hand",
          "Flock",
          "Pod"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  },
  {
    "name": "Science",
    "id": "knowledge",
    "theme": "yellow",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "Mole is a popular paste in Mexico. Mole is a mixture of chili’s and what other tasty ingredient?",
        "answer": "Chocolate"
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "What is the name of the famous art deco skyscraper in New York City?",
        "options": [
          "Trump Tower",
          "Chrysler building",
          "Empire State Building",
          "The New York Times Building"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "Select the names of “The Three Musketeers”.",
        "options": [
          "Chevy",
          "Topeka",
          "Athos",
          "Duke",
          "Porthos",
          "John Felton",
          "Aramis"
        ],
        "answer": [
          2,
          4,
          6
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "toggle-translate",
        "question": "Which is the correct translation of Zorro?",
        "options": [
          [
            "Zorro",
            "Dog"
          ],
          [
            "Zorro",
            "Sword"
          ],
          [
            "Zorro",
            "Fox"
          ],
          [
            "Zorro",
            "Coyote"
          ]
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select-item",
        "question": "If a 5,000 coupon bond has a coupon rate of 13 percent, then the coupon payment every year is ___",
        "options": [
          "650",
          "1,300",
          "None of These",
          "130"
        ],
        "answer": 0
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "How many counters does a backgammon player have?",
        "min": 0,
        "max": 30,
        "answer": 15
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "There is a patron saint of The Internet.",
        "answer": true
      },
      {
        "type": "alpha-picker",
        "question": " Which letter other than X scores 8 in Scrabble?",
        "answer": "J"
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "Four of the worst ten maritime disasters all took place in 1945. In which sea were all four ships sunk?",
        "options": [
          "Mediterranean sea",
          "Baltic Sea",
          "The Bermuda Triangle",
          "Black Sea"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select",
        "question": "The average of first 50 natural numbers is ",
        "options": [
          "25.30",
          "25.50",
          "25.00",
          "12.25"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  },
  {
    "name": "History",
    "id": "history",
    "theme": "blue",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "The first words spoken on the moon by Buzz Aldrin were these:",
        "start": "Contact ",
        "answer": "Light"
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select-item",
        "question": "The number of 3-digit numbers divisible by 6, is",
        "options": [
          "149",
          "166",
          "150",
          "151"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "Cleopatra was Egyptian.",
        "answer": false
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "The Rosetta Stone is the name of the limestone slab that became the key for deciphering ancient Egyptian hieroglyphics.",
        "answer": false
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "Prior to 1664 New York was called:",
        "start": "New ",
        "answer": "Amsterdam"
      },
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "What are the surnames of Bonnie and Clyde?",
        "options": [
          "Parson",
          "Parker",
          "Patterson",
          "Barlow",
          "Barret",
          "Barrow"
        ],
        "answer": [
          1,
          5
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "Joan of Arc, in the 15th century, was the first female promoted to this rank in the French army:",
        "options": [
          "Lieutenant",
          "Sergeant",
          "General",
          "Captain"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "In which year did William Shakespeare die?",
        "min": 1615,
        "max": 1635,
        "answer": 1616
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select",
        "question": "106 × 106 – 94 × 94 = ?",
        "options": [
          "2004",
          "2400",
          "1904",
          "1906"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "Which states did the United States gain after the Mexican War?",
        "options": [
          "Arizona",
          "New Mexico",
          "Louisiana",
          "California",
          "Nevada",
          "Utah",
          "Texas"
        ],
        "answer": [
          1,
          3,
          6
        ]
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  },
  {
    "name": "Geography",
    "id": "geography",
    "theme": "red",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "Name the other state in the USA that starts with the letter A:",
        "start": "Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, and ",
        "answer": "Arkansas"
      },
      {
        "type": "toggle-translate",
        "question": "Select which landmark to American state pairings are correct:",
        "options": [
          [
            "Las Vegas",
            "Arizona"
          ],
          [
            "Death Valley",
            "California"
          ],
          [
            "Mount Rushmore",
            "North Dakota"
          ],
          [
            "Fort Knox",
            "Kentucky"
          ],
          [
            "Kennedy Space Center",
            "Florida"
          ]
        ],
        "answer": [
          1,
          3,
          4
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "A person born in Lombardy is Italian.",
        "answer": true
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "Approximately how many kilometers of coastline does the United Kingdom have?",
        "min": 2000,
        "max": 5000,
        "step": 500,
        "answer": 2500
      },
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "Which three countries have fifty or more nuclear reactors?",
        "options": [
          "USA",
          "Russia",
          "Canada",
          "Brazil",
          "France",
          "Japan",
          "China"
        ],
        "answer": [
          0,
          4,
          5
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "What country would you visit to see Casablanca?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select-item",
        "question": "In which city was the 1992 Olympics?",
        "options": [
          "Atlanta",
          "Barcelona",
          "Seoul",
          "Sydney"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": " What food is named after a northern German city on the river Elbe?",
        "answer": "Hamburger"
      },
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "Select two countries that are linked by the Brenner Pass:",
        "options": [
          "Germany",
          "Croatia",
          "Austria",
          "Switzerland",
          "France",
          "Italy",
          "Czech Republic"
        ],
        "answer": [
          2,
          5
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select",
        "question": "Which of the following numbers gives 240 when added to its own square?",
        "options": [
          "15",
          "16",
          "18",
          "20"
        ],
        "answer": 0
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  },
  {
    "name": "Science and Nature",
    "id": "science",
    "theme": "green",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "What is the layer of the earth underneath the crust called?",
        "answer": "Mantle"
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select-item",
        "question": "The simplest form of 1.5 : 2.5 is ___",
        "options": [
          "6 : 10",
          "15 : 25",
          "0.75 : 1.25",
          "3 : 5"
        ],
        "answer": 3
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "What is the only cat in the world that can’t retract its claws?",
        "options": [
          "Meerkat",
          "Bobcat",
          "Cheetah",
          "Siamese"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "toggle-translate",
        "question": "Which chemical symbols are incorrect?",
        "options": [
          [
            "Helium",
            "He"
          ],
          [
            "Tungsten",
            "W"
          ],
          [
            "Lithium",
            "Lt"
          ],
          [
            "Nickel",
            "Ni"
          ],
          [
            "Copper",
            "C"
          ],
          [
            "Zinc",
            "Zn"
          ],
          [
            "Cadmium",
            "Cd"
          ],
          [
            "Potassium",
            "K"
          ],
          [
            "Silicon",
            "Sn"
          ]
        ],
        "answer": [
          2,
          4,
          8
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "The vitreous humour is found in the human eye.",
        "answer": true
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "What’s the third color of the rainbow?",
        "answer": "Yellow"
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "How many toes do most birds have?",
        "min": 2,
        "max": 12,
        "answer": 8
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "If the temperature in Centigrade is minus 40 degrees what is the temperature in Fahrenheit?",
        "min": -100,
        "max": 0,
        "step": 5,
        "answer": -40
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "What sort of creature is a fluke?",
        "options": [
          "Bird",
          "Insect",
          "Worm",
          "Bear"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-two-blanks",
        "question": "What two metals together make brass?",
        "answer": [
          "Copper",
          "Zinc"
        ]
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  },
  {
    "name": "TV & Movies",
    "id": "tvmovies",
    "theme": "purple",
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "type": "multi-select",
        "question": "Select the actors who played James Bond:",
        "options": [
          "Sean Connery",
          "Clive Owen",
          "Timothy Dalton",
          "David Niven",
          "Clint Eastwood",
          "Toby Stephens"
        ],
        "answer": [
          0,
          2,
          3,
          5
        ]
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "In which movie were Kevin Bacon, Bill Paxton, and Tom hanks on an aircraft?",
        "answer": "Apollo 13"
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "In which famous sci-fi film did Robert Patrick play an assassin?",
        "options": [
          "Blade Runner",
          "Terminator 2",
          "Watchmen",
          "Forbidden Planet"
        ],
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "type": "single-select",
        "question": " What is the unit of volume?",
        "options": [
          "Only units.",
          "Square units.",
          "Cubic units.",
          "None of These"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "How old is Bart Simpson?",
        "min": 6,
        "max": 13,
        "answer": 10
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "Where had King Kong lived before coming to New York in the 1933 film \"King Kong\"?",
        "end": "island",
        "answer": "skull"
      },
      {
        "type": "true-false",
        "question": "Stanley Kubrick directed the 1971 film \"THX 1138.\"",
        "answer": false
      },
      {
        "type": "picker",
        "question": "The film \"Ben Hur\" holds the record for winning more Oscars than any other movie. How many?",
        "min": 4,
        "max": 15,
        "answer": 11
      },
      {
        "type": "four-quarter",
        "question": "Which Spielberg film gives an unflattering account of Carcharodon Carcharias?",
        "options": [
          "Saving Private Ryan",
          "E.T.",
          "Jaws",
          "The Color Purple"
        ],
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "type": "fill-blank",
        "question": "In which film did Robert De Niro ask “Are you talkin’ to me?”",
        "answer": "Taxi Driver"
      }
    ],
    "scores": [
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0,
      0
    ],
    "solved": "false"
  }
]
